Chucky gets lucky.
Bride of Chucky is a horror, comedy film directed by Ronny Yu.
Chucky is reborn when his old flame, Tiffany, rescues his
battered doll parts from a police impound.
Chucky (voice), played by Brad Dourif.
Tiffany, played by Jennifer Tilly.
Jade, played by Katherine Heigl.
Jesse, played by Nick Stabile.
Damien, played by Alexis Arquette.
David, played by Gordon Michael Woolvett.
Bride of Chucky is a 1998 American black comedy slasher film
written by Don Mancini and directed by Ronny Yu.
The fourth mainline installment in the Child's Play franchise, it stars Jennifer
Tilly, Brad Dourif, John Ritter, Katherine Heigl, and Nick Stabile.
Unlike the first three films, Bride of Chucky takes a markedly
humorous turn towards self-referential parody.
It also departs from the Andy Barclay storyline of the first three films, focusing mainly on series villain Chucky, a doll
possessed by a serial killer, and his former lover and accomplice Tiffany, whose soul is also transferred into a doll.
Bride of Chucky was released on October 16, 1998, by Universal Pictures.
The film grossed over $50 million worldwide on a budget of $25
million and received mixed reviews from critics.
A sequel, Seed of Chucky, was released in 2004.
The film explores themes of voodoo, route 66, evil
doll, killer doll, serial killer.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.